<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Keith Schnakenberg</title>
    <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Keith Schnakenberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Keith Schnakenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accountability in Gubernatorial Elections: Theory and Estimation</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/structural-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/structural-elections/</guid>
      <description>Abstract My ongoing project focuses on methods for identifying and estimating the parameters of a game of infinitely repeated elections with adverse selection and moral hazard. In the game, candidates from two parties compete for office in each time period over an infinite horizon. Candidates have heterogeneous costs for expending effort to produce good outcomes in office. The voters cannot perfectly observe candidate types or effort and instead observe a noisy outcome that is correlated with effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoral and policy effects of campaign finance contributions</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/cf-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/cf-signal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signaling with reform: How the threat of corruption prevents informed policymaking</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/signaling-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/signaling-reform/</guid>
      <description>(with Ian Turner )
Abstract Lobbying is a potential source of corruption but is also a valuable source of information for policymakers. We analyze a game-theoretic model that shows how the threat of corruption affects the incentives of non-corrupt politicians to enlist the help of lobbyists to make more informed decisions. Politicians face a dilemma because voters cannot always tell whether a politician allows access to lobbyists in order to solicit corruption or to seek information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>