<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on Keith Schnakenberg</title>
    <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/tags/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on Keith Schnakenberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Keith Schnakenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://keith-schnakenberg.com/tags/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Climate Policy And Collective Action: A Comment</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/collectiveaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/collectiveaction/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In a recent issue of Global Environmental Politics, Aklin and Mildenberger (2020) argue against the prevailing characterization of climate change cooperation as a problem of free riding or collective action. The authors argue that models of collective action imply (1) policy reciprocity and (2) inaction in the absence of formal agreements to limit free riding. They argue that neither empirical implication is supported by an review of states&amp;rsquo; climate policy to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anger and Political Conflict Dynamics</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/emotions/</guid>
      <description>external_link=&amp;ldquo;https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/zmv85/&amp;quot;
Abstract Emotions shape strategic conflict dynamics. However, political science lacks theories integrating strategic and emotional concerns. We propose a model of intergroup conflict under incomplete information in which agents are sensitive to psychological motivations in the form of anger. In the model, agents become angry when they experience worse-than-expected outcomes and blame those bad outcomes on the intentional actions of another player. Friendly players who experience bad outcomes may act aggressively out of anger or because the outcomes contain information about the preferences of the other group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Money and Politician Learning</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/darkmoneypol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/darkmoneypol/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We study the consequences of campaign finance disclosure laws in a model of informative campaign finance. Contributions can affect electoral outcomes and also signal policy information to politicians. Under transparent contributions the equilibrium is one in which donors may make contributions that run counter to their electoral interests in order to signal good news regarding their preferred policy. We compare donor welfare when contributions reveal information across different campaign finance transparency regimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Money and Voter Learning</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/darkmoneyvoter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/darkmoneyvoter/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We provide a model of dark money in elections. A donor with extreme preferences relative to the voter is privately informed about the policy preferences and valence of a politician. Advertisements reveal information about valence and the voter can learn either through donor-funded advertisements or from neutral sources. Under transparency the voter always knows the source of a message. When the message is donor funded the voter concludes that the candidate is more likely to be extreme since the donor contributed money to that candidate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informative Campaigns, Overpromising, and Policy Bargaining</title>
      <link>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/overpromise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://keith-schnakenberg.com/project/overpromise/</guid>
      <description>external_link=&amp;ldquo;https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/asqk6/&amp;quot;
Abstract What is the relationship between policy positions taken in campaigns when the final policy outcome depends on other political actors? Why do candidates sometimes advocate policies in their campaigns that are unlikely or impossible to pass given the preferences of other actors in the government? We analyze a model in which candidates make non-binding policy platform announcements and then bargain with a veto player over the final policy if they take office.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>